日  听      マキ
日听校对       Syura
翻译        银苹果
翻译校对       Mam
"School Fair (43rd Ouran Fair)"
"The morning before the fair"
时间轴       黑猫与牛奶
压制      娜夏
"Preparing for the opening ceremony"
Take all of the tables to the salon
in the central building.
テーブルも皆中央棟のサロンに運んで
OP&ED       葉隠
Syura
诸神字幕组
Take all of the tables to the salon
in the central building.
- Right.
- Ah, be careful with that.
ああ　それ　気をつけて
Um... aren't school fairs
supposed to be more, I don't know,
あのう　学祭って　もっとこう　手作り感というか…
homemade-looking, like we've
made everything on our own?
全部自分たちで作るものじゃないんですか
You're talking about schools in general.
それは一般の学校の話だろう
What gets emphasized at Ouran Fair
is planning and leadership.
この桜蘭祭で重視されるのは企画力と統率力だ
Most of the students here are expected
to be future leaders by nature,
ここの学生たちのほとんどは将来のリーダーたる資質を期待され
so they are required to impress
everyone with their strengths.
その力をアピールすることが要求されている
Whoa, whoa!
That was good. We can
turn them over to you now.
うまいぞ　もう任せられるな
Haru-chan!
ハルちゃん
Climb aboard, Haruhi!
乗れ　ハルヒ
We're rehearsing for
Ouran Fair's special parade!
桜蘭祭スペシャルパレードの予行演習だ
"Horse-drawn carriage?"
Look, look, it's the boys
from the Host Club!
見て見て　ホスト部の皆さんよ
- How fantastic!
素敵ですわ
I want to ride with them, too!
私も乗りたい
Hey, you've gotten so you
can handle this, huh?
やるようになったじゃん
Kaoru, you should have
come practiced with me.
馨も一緒に練習すればよかったのに
Well, even twins will start to have
different interests and strong suits.
まっ　双子だって趣味や特技は違ってくるさ
It's kind of fun to have all of us
riding in a carriage like this, huh?
こうして皆で馬車に乗るのって　なんか楽しいね
Is it?
そうですか
In the actual parade tomorrow,
明日のパレード本番では中世フランス風に着飾って決めるからな
we're going to wow them
with medieval French outfits.
We even have a real flashy
costume for you, Haruhi.
ハルヒのど派手な衣装も用意してあるぞ
Flashy, you say?
ど派手ですか…
Well now, the opening
ceremony is starting.
さて　オープニングセレモニーの始まりだ
Let's make this Ouran Fair
one for the school history books.
学院の歴史に残る桜蘭祭にするぞ
Sure.
そうですね
"Ouran Fair Opening Ceremony"
"Central Building Salon"
"The Host Club is open
to the general public"
Remember,
いいか　学祭スペシャルイベントとして
as a special event during the school fair,
the Host Club will be open
to all of the parents and visitors,
父兄や来賓の皆様にも
我がホスト部を公開する今日と明日の二日間
so for today and tomorrow,
we will entertain them
even more extravagantly,
いつも以上に華やかに　咲き誇るように接客するのだぞ
and in full bloom than usual.
Look, Mother, this is the Host Club
I'm always telling you about.
ほら　お母様　あれがいつもお話してるホスト部よ
Isn't it fantastic?
素敵でしょう
I'm not so sure. To have them
be fussed over by all the girls,
どうかしら
少しばかりきれいだからって
just because they may be
somewhat good-looking...
それを鼻に掛けて女性にもてはやされようなんて
そうですね　マダム
Indeed, madam. It is true,
that may be indefensible.
確かに許してはいただけないかもしれません
After all, the real purpose
of this club is nothing more
なぜなら　この部の本当の目的は
"Gently..."
than meeting our selfish desires
to spend even the slightest moment
マダムのような美しい花と一時を過ごしたいという
with beautiful flowers
such as yourself, madam.
僕のわがままでしか…ないのですから
Oh, my...
もう　素敵ですわ
W-what a fantastic club you have here!
"Open for business using
counter-madam tactics"
Yes, you do!
ですわ
Thank you very much, madam.
ありがとうございます　マダム
Good grief.
Your button has come undone, Mitsukuni.
ボタンが外れてるぞ　光邦
エヘッ　ありがとう
Thank you.
My, how heartwarming!
もう　微笑ましい
きっとご兄弟ね　弟思いのいいお兄さん
I'm sure they must be brothers.
What a thoughtful older brother he is.
ちがーう
Wrong!
Father and Mother are both
so busy all the time,
父も母も多忙で
so we spent most of our time
alone, just the two of us.
僕らはほとんど二人きりで過ごしてきましたから
That is why we have both
become so hopelessly lonesome.
だから僕たち　どうしようもなく寂しがり屋なんです
- Oh, you poor boys!
ああ…かわいそう…
"Sob..."
Which mouth are they speaking out of?
どの口が物を言うか
In this club, one of our themes
is to acquire societal culture,
この部は社交的教養を身につけることもテーマとしておりますので
so we are able to research a wide
variety of customs, pastimes,
日頃より各国の行事や遊び
歴史的な民族衣装なども幅広く研究しております
and historic traditional dress from
countries all over, on a daily basis.
Oh, that is wonderful.
ほっ　素晴らしい
What an unashamedly
politic thing to say.
いけしゃあしゃあとは適当なことを…
I have to say, this sure
is a ritzy event.
それにしても　贅沢なイベントですね
It's too much money to be
spent on a mere school fair.
たかが学祭に　お金掛けすぎですよ
何を言うか
What are you talking about?
This grand campaign strategy is a chance
この機会に
我が桜蘭ホスト部の魅力を広く世間にアピールしようという
to show off the charm
of the Ouran Host Club
far and wide, throughout the world!
これは一大キャンペーン作戦なのだ…ああ
"Pinch!"
You're right, in that we have
overspent our budget on this.
確かに今回は予算を掛けすぎた
Kyoya...
鏡夜？
Use of this salon notwithstanding,
このサロンはいいとして
we had a classic carriage flown
in all the way from France.
わざわざフランスからクラシック馬車まで空輸して
As is always the case,
お前のわがまま企画には毎度のことながら手を焼かされる
I don't know how to deal with
all of your capricious plans.
Isn't that the truth?
ですよね
Haruhi! Hey, you be quiet!
ハルヒ
ええ　黙れ　黙れ
The whims of the Host King are
the whims that make everyone happy!
このホストキングのわがままこそ皆を幸せにするわがままなのだ
いらっしゃいませ
Welcome.
May I bring you something sweet to eat?
何か甘いものでもお持ちいたしましょうか
You are a member of the Host Club?
あなたもホスト部員？
Yes.
Father!
お父さん
"Father" is too familiar. Address me
as "Superintendent" while at school.
お父さんとは馴れ馴れしい
"School Board Chairman Yuzuru Suou"
学院では理事長と呼べ
Besides, I am here as a guest today.
それに今日は客としてきたんだぞ
"...Tamaki's father..."
Welcome, Superintendent.
いらっしゃいませ　理事長
Come, please take this seat over here.
さ　どうぞ　こちらの席へ
Thank you.
ありがとう
Kyoya- kun, this club owes everything
to your management, doesn't it?
鏡夜君　この部も　君が仕切ってくれればこそだな
愚息が　面倒をかけてるね
My son must give you no end of trouble.
Not at all. The Host Club
is here because of him.
いえいえ　彼あってこそのホスト部ですから
Can I get you anything?
何かご注文は？
"Whisper"
Yes... yes... as you wish.
はい　はい　かしこまりました
Haruhi, you have a request.
ハルヒ　ご指名だ
What!?
何？！
So, you're Fujioka Haruhi- kun, are you?
やぁ　藤岡ハルヒ君だね
Come, have a seat.
さ　掛けたまえ
By your leave.
失礼します
This man is Tamaki-senpai's father?
この人が環先輩のお父さん
They don't look that much alike...
あまり似てない…かな
I'm pleased to meet you. I was thinking
はじめまして
理事長にはもっと早くご挨拶しなければと思っていたのですが
that I should have paid my respects
to you sooner, Superintendent.
"Superintendent" is so stuffy.
You can... yes...
理事長だなんて水くさい
私のことは…そう
You can call me..."Uncle."
「お・じ・さ・ま」　と呼んでくれたまえ
He's Tamaki-senpai's father, all right.
やっぱり環先輩のお父さんだ
I've been so busy, I haven't been
able to get around the campus much,
どうにも多忙でなかなか学院にも顔を出せないが
but I am always hearing about
how exceptional you are.
君の優秀さはいつも耳にしているよ
はあ…どうも
Why, thank you.
If ever you have any trouble,
何か困ったこがあったら
feel free to come tell
your uncle at any time.
いつでも遠慮なくこのおじさまに言いなさい
Sure...
Father!
お父さん…
Call me "Superintendent"!
理事長と呼べ
What are you doing!?
何をしてるんですか
Remove your hands at once, please!
すぐにその手を放してください
Kyoya- senpai!
鏡夜先輩
This is the sort of ridiculous
club you've been in?
こんなふざけた部活動をやってたのか
That's Kyo-chan's father, right?
鏡ちゃんのお父さん…だよね
Yeah.
"Yoshio Otori"
Are you trying to embarrass me?
私に恥をかかせるつもりか
"Kyoya's father"
If it isn't Suou- san.
I'm sorry you had to see that.
これは　須王さん　お見苦しいところを
That was pretty harsh,
as exceptional as Kyoya- kun is.
手厳しいですな　鏡夜君は優秀なのに
For someone who has four
such fine children,
出来のいい子を四人も持ちながら
your avarice does run deep, indeed.
あんたはやっぱり欲が深いや
I've heard the news.
お話は聞いています
It's only a matter of time before
the press starts making noise.
マスコミが騒ぐのも時間の問題でしょうが
Please tell me you weren't
taking it out on him.
まさか八つ当たりではないでしょうな
Kyoya, are you okay?
鏡夜　大丈夫か
What a mean papa!
なんてパパさんだ
Yeah, to hit someone
wearing glasses like that.
眼鏡をかけた人を殴るなんてね
No, that's not what he meant.
いや　そういうことじゃないでしょう
Did he hit you because
you are in the Host Club?
ホスト部をやっているから殴られたんですか
It's all right.
いいんだ
I've been expecting it.
予想はしていたことだ
It was because... of the Host Club?
ホスト部の…せいなのか
Your capriciousness carries a high price.
わがままは高くつくものだ
Standing in a position of greater
responsibility than regular people
普通の人よりも責任ある立場に立つということは
also means that you are
no longer free to pursue
好きなこと　好きなもの
the matters you like, the items
you like, or the people you like.
そして好きな人を自由に追いかけなれなくなることでもある
Haruhi- kun!
ハルヒ君
Yes?
Thank you so much for taking
time out of your busy schedule
本日はお忙しい中ホスト部にお越しいただき
to come visit us at the Host Club today.
ありがとうございます
What do you want to do from here on?
これからお前はどうしたい
Do you want to take over
the Suou family?
須王の家を継ぎたいか
That would be a difficult choice.
それは難しい選択だぞ
I still have not been able
to find the answer.
私は未だにその答えを見つけられずにいる
Do you really know what
it is that you want most?
お前は自分が一番ほしいものが何か　本当に分かっているのか
Look.
あら　お祖母様がいらっしゃった
Your grandmother has come.
Grandmother! You were
good enough to come!
お祖母様　来てくださったのですね
Wow, that woman is
Tamaki- senpai's grandmother?
へぇ　あの方が環先輩のお祖母様ですか
I hate that woman.
僕　あの人嫌い
Come, have a seat inside.
さ　奥のお席へ
Do not touch me.
触らないで頂戴
You disgust me.
汚らわしい
Éclair- san, come over here.
エクレールさん　こちらにいらっしゃって
Oh, I was just...
あっ　先の…
Who is she?
誰？
For the duration of the school
fair today and tomorrow,
今日と明日の学祭の間　このエクレール嬢をエスコートしなさい
you are to escort Lady Éclair here.
"Éclair Tonnerre"
Is something wrong?
I'm telling you to.
どうしたの　私が言ってるのよ
I'm in your hands, Tamaki.
よろしく　環
Very well, Grandmother.
分かりました　お祖母様
I will do everything within my power
彼女に喜んでいただけるよう　全力を尽くします
to see that she will be happy.
Tama-chan isn't coming back, huh?
タマちゃん　戻ってこないね
Is he seriously planning to escort...
マジで学祭の間
...that girl for the duration
of the school fair?
あの子をずっとエスコートするつもりなのかな
Come, my princess,
さあ　姫　まいりましょう
let's be off.
Her name was Éclair,
or something like that...
エクレールとか何とか言ってたけど
...but who is that girl?
あの女の子　何者なの
I know that girl.
あの子知ってるわ
Renge-chan...
蓮華ちゃん
Éclair Tonnerre, the third
daughter of the renowned
エクレール・トネール
伯爵家の家柄でもあるフランスの名家　トネール家の三女
French Tonnerre family,
which descends from royalty.
Renge- kun, you did grow up
in France, too, and all.
蓮華君もフランス育ちだったな
そっ　トネール家は単に家柄がいいだけではなく
Yes, the Tonnerre family doesn't
simply have high social standing,
they are also the owners
of Grand Tonnerre, the company
最近わが国の企業を次々と買収している外資系企業として
that the financial world has
been clamoring over of late,
経済界で騒がれているあのグラントネール社のオーナーでもある
for being a foreign-funded firm, rapidly
buying up businesses in our country.
Of course,
もっとも　そのご令嬢がなぜ環に会いに来たのかは
we do not know why their daughter
has come here to see Tamaki...
知らないがな
What do you think?
いかがですか
The idea is to enjoy
a leisurely cruise on a gondola,
ゆっくりとゴンドラの船旅を楽しみながら
while being able to admire the works
of the members of the Art Club.
美術部員たちの作品を鑑賞できるという趣向です
It's boring. I don't care
about any student works.
退屈
学生の作品なんてどうでもいい
That's pretty harsh.
But I don't know what I can do.
これは手厳しい
しかし困ったな
Ouran Fair is a fair for the students.
この桜蘭祭は学生の祭りです
Where might I show you
that would please you?
どこへ案内すれば喜んでもらえるのかな
I want to hear you play the piano, Tamaki.
私　環のピアノが聞きたいな
Please.
お願い
We do not know why their daughter
has come here to see Tamaki...
そのご令嬢がなぜ環に会いに来たかは　知らないがな
In here?
こんな所で？
楽室ですから
It is a music room, after all.
This is the room where you always
conduct your Host Club thing?
ここがいつもあなたたちが
ホスト部とやらをやってるお部屋なんでしょう
I was watching you in the salon,
and you all seem to get along very well.
サロンで拝見させてもらったけど
皆　とても仲がいいのね
That is because the Host Club
is like a coming together of family.
それはもう　我がホスト部は家族同然の集まりですから
In Japan, they call pretending
to have a real family,
日本じゃ　本物の家族でもないのに　家族ごっこをするのを
even when it isn't one,
"playing house," don't they?
ままごとって言うんでしょう
Tamaki, you are making everyone else
環一人のわがままで皆が辛い思いをしてるんじゃないの
suffer because of your
capriciousness, aren't you?
眼鏡のホスト君　パパに殴られてたものね
I mean, that host with the glasses
was even struck by his papa, right?
I don't know how to deal with
all of your capricious plans.
お前のわがまま企画には毎度のことながら手を焼かされる
Is it possible that
everyone is actually
もしかしたら
本当に皆裏ではいろんなものを犠牲にしているのか
having to secretly give
up various other things?
It's true, Haruhi, who wants
to spend every minute she has
確かに弁護士を目指し
一分でも多く勉強していたいハルヒにだって
studying to be a lawyer, has been
made to give up her precious time,
毎日毎日部活を強制して　大切な時間を犠牲にさせている
forced to attend club
activities day in and day out.
Who is it?
誰？
Haruhi? What are you doing?
ハルヒ　何してる？
着替えに戻ってきたんですよ
I came back here to change outfits.
Senpai, you were the one who said
to change three times a day, right?
一日三回以上替えるって言ったのは先輩でしょう
To neglect the salon now, after
being the one to tell us to do so,
言い出した本人がサロンをほったらかして
everyone is upset at you.
皆怒ってますよ
Oh, my apologies.
Tamaki belongs to me right now.
あら　悪いわね
環は今　私のものだから
But then, somehow,
you seem to be jealous.
だけど　なんだかあなた　やきもち焼いてるみたい
Jealous!?
やきもち？
そうなのか　そうなのか　そうなのか　ハルヒ～
Is that true? Is that true?
Is that true, Haruhi?
No, it's not. All right,
I'm terribly sorry for disturbing you.
違いますよ
はいはい　お邪魔して申し訳ありませんでした
お邪魔って　おい　ハルヒ
Disturbing us? Hey, Haruhi-
何　環はあんな豆狸がいいの
What's this? Tamaki, you'd
rather have that little shrew?
失礼な
How rude! Please do not
call my little girl a shrew.
うちの娘を豆狸呼ばわりするのはやめてくれ
Your little girl...
娘ね
Your make-believe family is,
in the end, just make-believe.
ままごとの家族は所詮ままごと　代用品でしょう
A surrogate.
What are you doing!?
何をするんです…
Tamaki, I can give you
環が一番ほしいものを
the thing that you want most.
私はあげることができる
- My!
- How cute!
可愛い
Fantastic!
素敵
Haru-chan is so cute!
ハルちゃん　可愛い
Yeah.
Nice.
いいね
Where did his highness go?
殿はどこ行ったんだろう
一番楽しみにしてたくせに
He was looking forward
to this most of all.
Senpai was in Music Room #3.
He was with Lady Éclair.
楽室にいましたよ
エクレール嬢と一緒でした
Oh, what's this?
おっ　なんだ
That sounded a lot like jealousy.
それ結構やきもちっぽいぞ
Like I said, it is not!
だから　違いますって
だから？
"Like you said?"
Like you said?
Still, Tamaki- senpai is being
a bit irresponsible this time.
だけど
今回の環先輩は少し無責任ですよね
Ordinarily, you might call
it capriciousness, and it is that...
普段からわがままといえばわがままだけど
Well, let's give him a pass.
まっ　大目に見てやれ
It was none other than his grandmother
that ordered him, after all.
他ならぬ　お祖母様の命令だからな
Come, have a seat inside.
さ　奥のお席へ
Do not touch me.
触らないで頂戴
You disgust me.
汚らわしい
True, Tamaki- senpai's grandmother
did seem pretty cold to him.
確かに環先輩のお祖母様って環先輩に冷たい感じでしたね
Is there any reason for that?
何か理由でもあるんでしょうか
Well, everyone knows about it...
まっ　皆知ってることだけどさ
In short, his highness
is an illegitimate love child.
要するに殿ってお妾さんの子なのよ
Twenty-some years ago, the head
of the Suou family at the time
二十数年前　須王家の先代が若くして他界
passed away at a young age.
The superintendent of this school,
Mr. Yuzuru, entered into
この学院の現理事長である譲氏は母親の決めた相手と
what could be called a marriage
of political convenience
いわゆる政略結婚し
with a woman of his mother's choosing,
and succeeded the family.
その後を継ぎました
However, several years later,
the superintendent found true love
しかしながら数年後
理事長はフランスで出会った女性と本物の恋に落ちてしまいました
with a woman that he met in France.
And then, Tama-chan was born.
それで　タマちゃんが生まれたんだよね
Mother, I am leaving my wife,
and marrying her.
お母様　私は妻と別れ
彼女と結婚します
However, his grandma
was firmly against it.
けれど　祖母さんは大反対
His highness's mother is sickly,
殿のお母さんは病弱で　日本で暮らすには支障があったこともあり
and there were other obstacles
to having her live in Japan,
so his highness grew up there
in France until he was 14.
殿はそのまま十四歳までフランスで育ったんだ
His highness seems to have had
a happy childhood, in its own way,
殿にはそれなりに幸せな少年時代だったみたいだけど
but as time went on,
his mother's family business failed,
でも　やがてお母さんの実家が事業に失敗して
and after they had become
burdened with a great debt...
多額の負債をかかえちゃった時
...his grandma, who had started
worrying about there not being
須王家の跡取りがいないことを焦り始めた祖母さんが提案したんだ
any heirs to the Suou family,
came up with a proposal.
I will provide you with enough money
この先不自由なく暮らせるだけの金の工面はしてやろう
so that you be able to live
comfortably from now on.
In exchange, send Tamaki to Japan, alone.
その代わり　環だけは日本に寄こしなさい
Then, you and Tamaki will not be allowed
to see each other, ever again.
そして金輪際　あなたと環が会うことは許しません
That is the condition of my assistance.
それが援助の条件です
Wow...
そんな…
The current head of the Suou
family may be Mr. Yuzuru,
須王の当主は理事長の譲氏だが
but in actuality, the highest
power still belongs
事実上の最高権力者は今も会長職であるあのお祖母様だ
to its director, the grandmother.
What's more, Tamaki's mother
being of frail health,
おまけに環の母親は体が弱く
she knew what would happen
if she was left destitute
須王の援助なしで路頭に迷えば　どうなるかは知れていた
without the Suous' assistance.
And so...
だから…
I'm going. I'm going to Japan, alone.
行くよ　俺
一人で日本に行く
It will be all right. Please, Mom,
大丈夫だから
どうか　母さん　元気で
take care.
Afterward, whether out of sadness,
寂しさからか
それとも環を金と引き換えにしたことへの後ろめたさからか
or over guilt for having
traded Tamaki for money,
his mother apparently moved away
somewhere, and went into hiding.
母親はその後
身を隠すようにどこかへ移り住んだらしい
Currently, her whereabouts are unknown.
現在は行方不明だそうだ
And so, ever since, Tamaki has
not seen his mother even once.
だから環はそれ以来
母親と一度も会っていない
I won't ever be able to see Mom again?
もう　お母さんには会えないの
I never knew.
He's always so cheerful,
知らなかった
普段はあんなに明るいけど
I didn't know he'd had
such a painful upbringing.
そんな辛い生い立ちで
If I had been Tamaki-senpai,
もし自分が環先輩だったら
I wonder if I could keep from
resenting my grandmother.
あのお祖母様を恨まずにいられるかな
It's easy to feel sorry for him,
同情するのは簡単だが
but I'm glad that Tamaki
is who he is now.
でも俺は環が今の環でよかったと思っている
He will be fine.
あいつは大丈夫さ
Having accepted everything
he's been through, he is here now,
全てを受け入れた上で　あいつは今ここにいるんだ
in the Host Club.
このホスト部にね
Ah, Tama-chan!
タマちゃん
I have an important
announcement for everyone.
皆に大事な報告がある
I have decided to get engaged
to Lady Éclair Tonnerre here.
俺はこのエクレール・トネール嬢と婚約することにした
Further, the Host Club will be
dissolved following Ouran Fair.
それから　ホスト部はこの桜蘭祭が終わり次第
解散する
That is all.
以上だ
To be honest, I thought that you
were all just the strangest people.
正直　自分は皆のことを
何ておかしな人たちだろうって思いました
I mean, serving as hosts,
in a club, after school?
放課後の部活でホストだなんて
The final episode,
"This is Our Ouran Fair"
All of you, I...
自分は皆のこと…